<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Will Ingarfield</title>
		<link>https://sad-williams-6cde72.netlify.com/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Will Ingarfield</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 20:48:57 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://sad-williams-6cde72.netlify.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Deploying a Hugo site with Netlify</title>
			<link>https://sad-williams-6cde72.netlify.com/posts/hugo-netlify/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 20:48:57 -0600</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sad-williams-6cde72.netlify.com/posts/hugo-netlify/</guid>
			<description>I figured it might be useful to post some quick notes on how I set this site up. When I was looking for tools to use, I wanted a low maintenance static site generator that did not require a lot of web design knowledge. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of how Hugo works so I decided to give it a shot with Netlify.
Creating your first site For this I pretty much followed the Hugo quickstart exactly.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>I figured it might be useful to post some quick notes on how I set this site up. When I was looking for tools to use, I wanted a low maintenance static site generator that did not require a lot of web design knowledge. I&rsquo;m a big fan of how Hugo works so I decided to give it a shot with Netlify.</p>

<h2 id="creating-your-first-site">Creating your first site</h2>

<p>For this I pretty much followed the <a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/" target="_blank">Hugo quickstart</a> exactly. It&rsquo;s important to check if your theme has an example <code>config.toml</code> because often themes will have custom parameters in this. I decided to make my theme a submodule of my blog repo because I am (probably) the only one who is going to be maintaining this site so simple cloning is not a concern to me. I would look more into <code>git subtree</code> or simply cloning the theme repo if your site is going to be maintained by multiple people.</p>

<h2 id="deploying-to-netlify">Deploying to Netlify</h2>

<p>This was honestly the easiest part of the process and something I was very impressed by. Once I had committed my site repo to Github it was just a few clicks to get it deployed on Netlify. Make sure that your <code>HUGO_VERSION</code> environment variable is set to something somewhat recent. If you are using a theme that requires <a href="https://gohugo.io/news/0.43-relnotes/" target="_blank">Hugo Extended</a> (read: SASS/SCSS support) to build, make sure that the <code>resources/_gen/assets</code> directory is being tracked in your repo so that the Netlify build will skip the asset generation steps. This may be fixed in a newer version of Netlify. (<a href="https://github.com/netlify/build-image/issues/182" target="_blank">See here</a>)</p>

<p>Overall, I&rsquo;m really impressed by how easy this was to set up. It has been mostly hands free on my part and I plan to use this setup for future static site projects.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Hello World</title>
			<link>https://sad-williams-6cde72.netlify.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 16:31:16 -0600</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sad-williams-6cde72.netlify.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
			<description>This is my first post. 🎉 I created this site using Hugo and I am hosting using Netlify.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first post. 🎉 I created this site using <a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank">Hugo</a> and I am hosting using <a href="https://www.netlify.com/" target="_blank">Netlify</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
